A Metal Cardbot from the Sky!
It's real, I swear!
You may find it hard to believe,
but all of this is really happening!
What is she up to?
Apparently the video of the Metal Cardbots Vera uploaded is getting a ton of views.
Even overseas!
What? Overseas?!
Hrgh! I'm filming a report right now, can't you be quiet?!
Uh, sorry!
What do you mean, it's "getting tons of views overseas"?
I'm saying it already has over 5 million views!
What?!
But it seems the reviews are mixed.
"That's some good CG."
"It's like I'm watching a blockbuster movie."
"Just a copy of another robot anime."
"Is anyone actually falling for this prank?"
I'm so fed up!
How many times do I have to say this is not a fake video!
I have never used any kind of CGI!
Uh, h-hey! Hello?!
It seems she's been getting prank calls and harassment from malicious commenters.
I'm starting to feel bad for her...
Rrgh! Huh?
Who is it this time?
Hello. I am Fleta from Belmeha Island.
I became a fan of yours after seeing your videos.
I believe that your videos are real.
I'll be visiting Mowtown tomorrow...
So I'd like to meet up with you and share some information!
Yes! I knew there would be someone out there who believes me!
OMG, I can't wait to meet you, Fleta!
And... I take that back.
She just doesn't give up, does she?
I guess not.
Huh? A friend from overseas?
He said he was a fan of her Metal Cardbot videos.
That doesn't sound good.
I want to keep the Metal Cardbots a secret from as many people as possible.
But guys... everyone here already knows, anyway.
I think Crest is already on to us too.
Why are you chasing people away?!
Now that they've seen them with their own eyes...
I don't think we can keep making up excuses.
Everyone's been letting their guard down...
We need some special training!
Alright!
You're all here to train to either transform into your vehicle mode,
or hide before people see you!
We're ready!
Okay. The moment I turn around, transform or find cover!
1... 2... 3... 4... 5...
6-7-8-9-10!
Dexter... in or out. You have to pick one.
Mega Trucker, I can see you!
You all failed!
But, where did Shadow X go?
You gotta be quick, just like m-
Waah!
You could have just turned your stealth mode on.
You flunked the test too.
First, we need to find out who sent that email to Vera.
Kind of a strange place to... meet a guest from overseas.
Yeah, it's not even a coffee shop. It's a little strange.
Crest?!
What are you guys doing here?
Well... we were...
We are... lost, you see?
The police officer told us to wait here while he calls our parents!
That is the worst lie ever...
Crest!
Fancy seeing you here!
Hello, Vera.
Wow, what a coincidence!
What are you two doing here?
They told me they're lost.
What?! Our school is right around the corner!
Hehe... uh, anyway,
weren't you meeting the fan who sent you that email?
I guess word spreads fast, huh?
Yes. We agreed to meet here.
Here?
Looks like he's here now!
Is he arriving in that?
Careful, Jun! That plane is...
...could it be?
A Metal Cardbot?
Alerting all pedestrians!
Please evacuate the area immediately!
Hm.
A... A robot?
Nice to meet you, Vera.
E-excuse me... how do you know my name?!
My name is Fleta Z.
I am a fan of yours.
Y-You mean...
This is the guy who sent you the email?
The views will be out of this world...
Fleta Z!
Stop doing things that will alarm the people of this planet!
We've been trying to live among them after losing our home!-
B-Blue Cop!
Landing is not permitted in this area. Please evacuate the area immediately.
Does he think he's hiding?
Blue Cop, I'll take your letter of apology later.
Hey, you!
Are you talking to me?
Why did you send Vera that email?
What are you really after?
Your accusations hurt me.
Like I said earlier... I am her fan.
She is... my hope and light.
A flute?
How can he play that without a mouth...?
It's a long story.
He even talks while playing the flute...
I crash landed on an island called Belmeha
On the opposite end of the Earth.
Where I landed,
I couldn't find any Metal Cardbots nearby.
So I was alone, in the depths of the jungle.
Then, one day... a big turning point arrived.
Turning point?
I was able to find out more about this planet
thanks to the machine they left behind.
...This is?
That's when I found out...
...that I wasn't alone.
That there were other Metal Cardbots that had landed on this planet besides me.
So you thought that you would be able to find your fellow Metal Cardbots through Vera.
Is that right?
Yes.
If that's all, then we'd like to welcome you.
Right, Blue Cop?
Yes.
Let's work together to allow the Metal Cardbots and humans to coexist peacefully.
I refuse.
What do you mean?
I was wondering while watching those videos...
Why do these Metal Cardbots have to live in hiding?
I told you.
For us Metal Cardbots to live peacefully on this planet-
We need to have some patience?
I'm not buying it.
Why are we the only ones who have to hide?
What exactly is your point here?
You said you wanted humans and Metal Cardbots to coexist.
So we should be able to show our true selves in public
and not have to live in hiding.
I don't want you to have to hide either...
Jun.
But...
We have no choice.
If a giant robot just starts walking around town,
That would send most people flying into panic!
We should be careful about how we do it, and take our time...
So it's you.
The leader of evil that keeps us imprisoned!
W-What do you mean...
Give me the Metal Breath!
If you refuse... then I'll take it by force.
H-hey... hang on!
Beak Arrow!
Blue Cop!
It's just a little scratch. It's nothing, Jun.
You shouldn't put yourself in danger like that! Come back, Blue Cop!
Jun! Let me handle this guy!
Alright. Thank you, Mega Trucker!
Metal Breath, pickup!
Mega Trucker, setup!
Hey, big guy! That was a cowardly move, firing your bow out of nowhere like that!
Hm. I suppose I wasn't being fair.
I'll let you have the first move this time.
What?
Mega Trucker, Mega Power Tackle!
Mega Power Tackle!
Where do you think you're going?
I never said I'd take it sitting down!
Those puny arrows are nothing to me!
If you think that was all, you are sorely mistaken!
I didn't even need to block it!
Mega Trucker, behind you!
Huh? What?
Don't look away, even for a second!
Mega Trucker!
It's dangerous here.
Let's take Vera somewhere safe!
But it looks like the fun has only just begun. I'm staying.
W-What are you saying?!
I want to see it... What Jun is trying to protect.
What he's... protecting?
Shadow X! Spinning Cutter!
Spinning Cutter!
Shadow X, go after him!
If it's an aerial battle, I'm your guy!
Looks like you haven't figured it out yet.
That I'm vastly superior to you in every way. Speed, range, everything!
What was that?
Waah!
As well as mobility.
So long.
Shadow X!
Shadow X, are you alright?
I'm going to come get you! Hang in there!
Because of the Metal Breath,
entrusted to the chosen one by the will of the great Deus Machina,
Metal Cardbots will never truly be free.
Now.
Please hand over the Metal Breath.
Let me handle this!
No, I'll do it!
Hold on. You will only become a dart board if you don't have a strategy against those arrows of light.
Right. We have to figure out...
a way to disarm him.
Now, hurry!
I will never... let you have this!
Excuse me?
You heard me!
This is a token of friendship between me and Blue Cop!
Jun...
I see...
How touching!
Hm.
Now I see. So that's what you're trying to protect.
Come here, Wild Guardy!
Huh?!
Who are you?!
Wild Guardy?
Buh- Huh- Whuh?-
What the heck is going on here?!